God maintain I and Kyle show from
Lewistown Montana
atomic Western called Bochner since 2008
I came on starting teaching technology
when I first started and now it kinda
expanded into a few other
topics I grew up in the auction business
life my dad's an auctioneer
me and my great grandfather was action
auctioneers well im
I was born into business basically is
something that I
I've always believed in something that
I've really always in some way shape or
form wanna do you
unknown living the dream today I'm
partners with my dad ensure margin
Realty lewistown montana
we are specialize in a wide range
martian
merchandise from antiques collectibles
farm/ranch equipment
to real estate and then I sell cattle
several times a week
and the rain production sale any money
mine
the auction industry is something that
I've always believed and I think that as
our chinny years is our duty to
to train the next generation we're in
this together
got a lot of competitors this business
we all do is watch years
I also got a lot of friends and I think
that's something that
that we really bring the forefront here
Westergaard functionaries
we we are able to show students what
it's like to be in this business to be
professional
and giving back to the industry
something that
did I guess I've always believed in this
is my way up
doing a small portion their introducing
new auctioneers
into this business that child's here
the topics that are covered include have
been calling
I in technology with regard to
technology in its ever-changing
we as auctioneers need to be on the
cutting edge in that I feel an offer
that to our customers
not not only the buyers but the seller's
that we work with and I think that is
the curriculum that we can give them
here
give these young auctioneers here the
BCA will help them step right into them
when they head out
on their own and margins with that said
in all the
technology it live simulcast options and
internet only options that will even
talk about
there still a big need for bid callers
and will spend a lot of time talking
about
how to construct a chance how to build a
foundation is based on clarity
based on those numbers that we that we
drill on hammer on
when you leave here you will have the
Foundation's up having a chance of a
champion
teaching here Westergaard auctioneering
his given me an opportunity
to give back to a profession that I
believe very strongly in something like
grew up and have a passion for
and I loves bringing a new students into
the auction business and helping them
find their place in it
we look around the the auction community
we see competitor
more more matter we see for years and i
think thats
the beginning along those relationships
right here at auction school
when we can
help the young next-generation
auctioneers head right
head first in the industry Western
graduate has a certain existing
said go around the country you'll
typically here
be able to pick up where auctioneer from
by the sound of their chair
I believe that you can pick out a
Western graduate
in about any crowd they have a distinct
rhythm about them
and as sting clarity which is is one of
the most important thing
we do is on its bid callers you is
convey the price they were asking for if
they can understand
I'll were on a job and I think the
clarity and
and the rhythm latest hot here is
certainly evident
in those dues to go out he's comes said
the quality construction here
Westergaard functionary in my opinion
is second to none first of all the the
instructors are all successful
auctioneers
voice specialist cells full time in the
industry in some capacity
the comparable wide spectrum of
different segments of the industry from
livestock auction years to real estate
benefit auction
specialists to personal property
auctioneers
agricultural equipment auctioneer so a
student here really gets
to see everything that this auction
industry
has ended
my favorite part about being an
auctioneer's is the business
everything that we teach your with
regard to communication dealing with
people in
and of course the bid call it's all my
favorite there's nothing to compare to
stand and sit behind the microphone
working on behalf of the Seller selling
their assets and
and rush that comes from that and
the ability to help people naturally
what I thrive on old
the limit a class size here allows me
and the other instructors
time for individual training everybody's
got different needs
with regard to the bid call with regard
to the business everybody is in a
different spot
and with the smaller class size it
allows us to
assist each one of those students and
get to where they need to go
every day we had a new level with
technology and
in SD the influence that has had on the
auction industry is no different as
having a lot of other industries
but this industry is headed up and
there's a lot of opportunities that have
opened up to auctioneers in the last
several years that weren't there years
ago
internet only auctions different ways to
market our product and our services
on the Internet a this is a is a great
time to get the business because
right now there is so much more in our
fingertips than ever before
there still a need for good
bit taller but there's a lot of other
things that can be incorporated into an
auction business the killer in here
I found my chance from the foundation
that's based on your WC a and then
listening to a lot of other auctioneers
most on WC graduates and everybody all
know
everybody will develop their own style
as time goes on
and in that style really is starting
right here an auction school
when you go out into the business you
start conducting real live auctions
that style only role in only develop
over time
and eventually you'll be a master 0
me